DHRUV VERMA

Department of Computer Science, University of Toronto 40 St. George St, Toronto, ON, Canada

✓ www.dhruv-verma.com

@ dhruvverma@cs.toronto.edu

3 Dhruv Verma - Profile

OVERVIEW

I'm a Ph.D. student at the University of Toronto advised by Dr. Alex Mariakakis, working at the intersection of emerging ubiquitous technologies and human-centered computing. My research focuses on building practical, unobtrusive, and deployable sensing systems that have applications in healthcare, context awareness, virtual & augmented reality, and novel interactions.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto | Toronto, Canada

2021 - Present

Ph.D. in Computer Science Advisor: Alex Mariakakis

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi | Delhi, India

2017 - 2021

B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

- 4. Vimal Mollyn, Karan Ahuja, **Dhruv Verma**, Chris Harrison, Mayank Goel. *Under Submission at Proceedings of the ACM 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing (CHI'22).*
- 3. **Dhruv Verma**, Sejal Bhalla, Dhruv Sahnan, Jainendra Shukla, and Aman Parnami. 2021. ExpressEar: Sensing Fine-Grained Facial Expressions with Earables. *In Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive Mobile Wearable & Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT'21)* 5, 3, Article 129 (Sept 2021), 28 pages. https://doi.org/10.1145/3478085
- 2. **Dhruv Verma**, Kshitij Gulati, Vasu Goel, and Rajiv Ratn Shah. 2020. Fashionist: Personalising Outfit Recommendation for Cold-Start Scenarios. *In Proceedings on the 28th ACM International Conference on Multimedia (MM'20)*. https://doi.org/10.1145/3394171.3414446
- 1. **Dhruv Verma**, Kshitij Gulati and Rajiv Ratn Shah. 2020. Addressing the Cold-Start Problem in Outfit Recommendation Using Visual Preference Modelling. *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Multimedia Big Data (BigMM'20)*. https://doi.org/10.1109/BigMM50055.2020.00043

DHRUV VERMA / CV 1/2

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

 Research Assistant University of Toronto Computational Health and Interaction (CHAI) Lab, Advised by Dr. <u>Alex Mariakakis</u> Leading a project on performing robust and scalable gait analysis in everyday living environments. 	Sept. 2021 - Present
 Visiting Student Researcher Carnegie Mellon University Smart Sensing for Humans (SMASH) Lab, Advised by Dr. Mayank Goel Worked on a novel privacy-preserving activity recognition system. Work submitted to ACM CHI 2022. 	June 2020 - May 2021
 Undergraduate Research Assistant IIIT Delhi Weave Lab & HMI Lab, Advised by Dr. <u>Aman Parnami</u> & Dr. <u>Jainendra Shukla</u> Created a novel facial expression recognition system leveraging motion sensing on wireless earbuds. Work accepted to ACM UbiComp 2021 Built a novel framework for intergrating human affect & cognitive states in context-aware applications. 	Dec. 2018 - May 2021
AWARDS & HONORS	
Mitacs Globalink Research Internship Award	Summer 2020
ACADEMIC SERVICE	
Feature Editor, ACM XRDS Magazine Student Volunteer, ACM UbiComp/ISWC Student Volunteer, ACM UIST	2021 - Present 2020, 2021 2020
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	
Teaching Assistant, University of Toronto Introduction to Image Understanding Teaching Assistant, IIIT Delhi Privacy and Security in Online Social Media Teaching Assistant, IIIT Delhi Prototyping Interactive Systems	Fall 2021 Winter 2021 Fall 2019

REFERENCES

Alex Mariakakis (Assistant Professor, University of Toronto)
Aman Parnami (Assistant Professor, IIIT Delhi)
Jainendra Shukla (Assistant Professor, IIIT Delhi)
Mayank Goel (Assistant Professor, Carnegie Mellon University)

- Last updated: Oct. 24, 2021 -

DHRUV VERMA / CV 2/2